Karthik Soundara Rajan

Urban and Transportation Planner

Phone: +1(347) 217-5621 Blog: www.urbplankarthik.blog Email: chamzkarthik@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/karthiksoundar

Summary

Highly organized and self-motivated Urban and Transportation Planner with 2 years of progressive experience in Transportation, urban/community development primarily in the Capital region of NYS. Complemented with expertise knowledge in Transportation planning regulations & resources and modern practices & principles of urban/regional planning. Profound knowledge in collecting, analyzing, interpreting, and presenting neighborhood, zoning, and other city-level planning data through effective field investigations, surveys, and research skills. Possess strong interpersonal skills to effectively communicate with the Town/City Council, staff, and residents. Best Practice Awardee for the studio project (FALL 2018) - Saratoga Springs Natural Resource Inventory.

Expertise & Skills

Comprehensive Development Plans
Infrastructure Development Plans
Micro Economic Development
Policy Formulation for Economic Development
Real Estate Development
Funds/Grant Sources Analysis
4 Stage Modeling (Transportation)
Street Inventory Appraisal/Suggestion
Traffic and Travel Characteristics
EIA (Environmental Impact Analysis)
Site Analysis
Planning project proposal and formulation
Statistical analysis and Interpretation

(Chi-square, SEM Modeling, Correlations)
Scenic Analysis
Airport Disaster Preparedness
Neighborhood Development Plan
Regional Planning
Processing and creative presentation of data.
Planning Laws, Development regulations of
New York State.

Software Packages:

Microsoft Office, Auto Cad, ArcGIS, Photoshop, Indesign, Illustrator, SPSS, Sketchup, Envi, Fusion (LIDAR), Vissim.

Education

Master's in Urban and Regional Planning(SP Transportation)
State University of New York, Albany

August 2017 - May 2020

Bachelor of Planning

August 2011 - May 2015

School of Planning and Architecture, Vijayawada

Academic Projects

Bachelor of Planning

Thesis: The Changing Pattern of Real Estate in the Periphery of Bangalore, Karnataka, India.

Lab 7: Metropolitan Regional Plan a case of VGTM (Vijayawada, Guntur, Tenali, and Mangalgiri) (Krishna and Guntur District of Andhra Pradesh), India.

Lab 6: Urban Development Plan Tumkur, Karnataka, India. [Project Blog Link]

Lab 5: Area Development Plan Srirangam, Tamil Nadu, India. [Project Blog Link]

Lab 4: Traffic & Transport Study (Vijayawada, Andhra Pradesh)

Masters in Regional Planning

Studio: Information for Natural Resource Inventory, City of Saratoga Springs, New York. [Blog Link]

Research: Integration of UAS Technologies into the Airport Ecosystem

Work Experience

Graduate Student Planning Intern

June 2019-May 2020

Capital District Regional Planning Commission, Albany NY

Project 1: Technical assistance in planning for Bethlehem, NY. [Summary Blog Link]

Key Comp: Comparison to peer towns, Demography, Economic Development, and Mapping.

Project 2: Technical assistance in planning for Coeymans, NY. [Summary Blog Link]

Key Comp: Community profile, Growth projection, Mapping resources, Summary of prior planning efforts, Comp plan best practices, funding resources for planning efforts, and economic development strategies.

Project 3: Technical assistance in planning for Menands, NY. [Summary Blog Link]

Key Comp: Community food access, and security analysis. Development of strategies for the improvement of food access such as developing alternative transportation options and improving the available food and bolstering the existing grocery options within the community.

Other activities: Involved in mapping aspects of the Watervliet reservoir preservation study. Created 3-D modelling for building a Green-wall in the south of Albany, NY.

Independent Planning Researcher

Jan 2017 - June 2017

Tamil Nadu Institute of Urban Studies, Coimbatore India

Summarized the existing public housing policies of TN, India. Research of existing Real Estate policies in TN. Research of Smart City projects in India. Best practices for Comprehensive plans, District resources analysis.

Urban Planning Associate

Mar 2016 - Dec 2016

Headway Mapping Solutions, Coimbatore India

Mapping and Assessment of Informal housing, urban infrastructure, local service delivery in Coimbatore Municipal Corporation. Feasibility study for Slum resettlement (HUDCO)

Infrastructure Planning Intern

May 2014 - June 2014

Consortium for DEWATS Dissemination Society, Bangalore India

Surveying and mapping for the decentralized sanitation infrastructure in Bangalore, India. Contributed to the preparation of concept notes and brochures.

Reference

Catherine T. Lawson Ph. D.

Planning & Geography Department The University at Albany

Albany, NY

Phone: 518-442-4775 lawsonc@albany.edu

Mark A. Castiglione, AICP

Executive Director, CDRPC

Albany, NY

Phone: 518-453-0850 mark@cdrpc.org

Kate Maynard, AICP

Director of Planning and Economic Development, CDRPC

Albany, NY

Phone: 518-453-0850 kate.maynard@cdrpc.org